Stamatios Morellas

Plymouth, MN • (612) 860-1488 Web: https://stamatimorellas.com Email: smorellas@protonmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/stamatim

OBJECTIVE

Seeking position as a Software Engineer

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Motivated and creative Software Engineer with 4+ years of shared experience in Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Software Development Practices, Operating Systems, and Software Architecture. Growing interest and continuous learning in Blockchain, Machine Learning, and UI/UX Design.

EDUCATION

Iowa State University

Aug 2016 – Nov 2020

Bachelor of Science – Software Engineering
Ames, IA

Providence Academy Sep 2012 – May 2016

High School Diploma Plymouth, MN

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer (Contract)

Jun 2020 – Aug 2020

ProNex Inc.

Updated to site structure and theme to make navigation less tedious; Collaborated with marketing team to make WordPress site more informative to users; Ensured copy consistency for better keyword performance; Reformatted images for higher-resolution and better user-experience.

Head of Digital Media

Jul 2019 – Jun 2020

Blest Sinners Clothing Co.

Created, managed, and maintained our organization's WordPress <u>website</u>; Monitored user traffic on website and social media using various analytics tools; Enhanced brand awareness by curating content for Facebook advertising; Utilized Adobe Creative Suite to optimize content for social platforms.

Machine Learning Research Intern

Jun 2018 – Aug 2019

University of Minnesota Medical Center, <u>RADLAB</u>

Created and managed lab datasets using GitHub; Wrote a <u>tutorial</u> for the lab team to understand how to interact with the git repository; Collected, filtered, and analyzed patterns of time series data using Julia; Evaluated data and explored techniques for identifying adolescent depression in fMRI scans by implementing LSTM deep neural networks in Python.

Lab Intern

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

University of Minnesota

Evaluated user interfaces on a <u>project</u> for annotating cancer tomography scans; Acquired valuable knowledge of front-end technologies used in the system such as HTML/CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and PHP; Established expertise with heuristic evaluation methods, a critical tool for software enhancement and user experience testing.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

ML Toolkit - View Project

Personal Project (Ongoing)

Building a repository of templates for common machine learning models; Utilizing Python and Jupyter Notebooks to build templates for common machine learning topics including regression, classification, NLP, and deep learning.

Nodekraft Resources - View Project

Team Project – (Ongoing)

Building an open-source knowledge base application with a team of developers that offers curated programming and design resources to educate people on the tools available in the digital ecosystem; Developing a client-facing application in ReactJS for users to browse resource information in a purposeful and responsive way; Creating a custom API for fetching resource information from MongoDB.

Warehouse Inventory Automation – View Project

Senior Design Project

Designed and developed a full warehouse inventory management system using MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, and Node.js for my two semester-long senior design project at <u>Iowa State University</u>; Created a simulated warehouse environment for a flying drone using open-source WeBots platform to scan and send item barcodes to MongoDB server; Challenges included dynamically learning new things, adapting to COVID-19 restrictions on our project, and getting used to collaborating in a fully-remote team environment.

Image Processor – <u>View Project</u>

Academic Project

Implemented an image processor in Java; Used matrices, tuples, and stitching to manipulate image pixels; Learned how to classify pixels in photos based on factor of importance to resize images appropriately.

Web Search Engine - View Project

Academic Project

Implemented a rudimentary web search engine in Java; Practiced fundamental techniques relating to array list sorting, search algorithms, and Big-O notation; Gained understanding of trees and directed graphs.

CookBuddy - View Project

Academic Project

A semester-long team project for my software development practices course at Iowa State University; Designed and developed the front-end for our client-server Android application using Java and modern UI/UX design principles; Challenges included getting familiar working in a scrum environment, learning Spring Framework, and web sockets.

Hash Table Generator - View Project

Academic Project

Implemented a hash table construction algorithm in Java; Gained valuable insight into graph data structures and hash tables.